<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/12/2017 3:17:47 PM -->
<GameData>

	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_TITLE">
			<Text>Mali</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Credits</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>All information was gathered from Wikipedia:[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]<COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mali_Empire</COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT>[NEWLINE]<COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mali</COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT></Text>[NEWLINE]<COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Musa_I_of_Mali</COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The Mali Empire, also historically referred to as the Manden Kurufaba, sometimes shortened simply to Manden, was an empire in West Africa from c. 1230 to c. 1610. The empire was founded by Sundiata Keita and became renowned for the wealth of its rulers, especially Musa Keita. The Manding languages were spoken in the empire. It was the largest empire in West Africa and profoundly influenced the culture of West Africa through the spread of its language, laws and customs.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Climate and Terrain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Mali lies in the torrid zone and is among the hottest countries in the world. The thermal equator, which matches the hottest spots year-round on the planet based on the mean daily annual temperature, crosses the country. Most of Mali receives negligible rainfall and droughts are very frequent. Late June to early December is the rainy season in the southernmost area. During this time, flooding of the Niger River is common, creating the Inner Niger Delta. The vast northern desert part of Mali has a hot desert climate with long, extremely hot summers and scarce rainfall which decreases northwards. The central area has a hot semi-arid climate with very high temperatures year-round, a long, intense dry season and a brief, irregular rainy season. The little southern band possesses a tropical wet and dry climate, very high temperatures year-round with a dry season and a rainy season.</Text>
		</Row>




		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MALI_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>Musa was a devout Muslim, and his pilgrimage to Mecca made him well-known across northern Africa and the Middle East. His procession reportedly included 60,000 men, including 12,000 slaves[19] who each carried 4 lb (1.8 kg) of gold bars and heralds dressed in silks who bore gold staffs, organized horses, and handled bags. Musa gave the gold to the poor he met along his route. Musa not only gave to the cities he passed on the way to Mecca, including Cairo and Medina, but also traded gold for souvenirs. It was reported that he built a mosque every Friday. But Musa's generous actions inadvertently devastated the economy of the regions through which he passed. In the cities of Cairo, Medina, and Mecca, the sudden influx of gold devalued the metal for the next decade. Prices on goods and wares greatly inflated. To rectify the gold market, on his way back from Mecca, Musa borrowed all the gold he could carry from money-lenders in Cairo, at high interest. This is the only time recorded in history that one man directly controlled the price of gold in the Mediterranean.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
	
</GameData>